[music]
[Instructor] All right. So we've made
it so that our Background repeats
every time it goes back through
but it does look
a little bit weird.
It's not exactly perfect.
You can definitely tell
that something's wrong here
but at least our Player jumps,
and they're still happy so that's good.
So in order to make our Background
transition seamlessly back and forth,
we're going to use some new
variables to be able to do so.
But first what we want to do is
we're actually going to use
one of our Box Colliders to help us,
with this problem.
So on our Background,
we're going to add a Component,
and then we're going to look
for a Box Collider.
And now you see
that our Box Collider wraps
entirely around our Background
which is perfect
because once again,
that means that there's less
that I have to do myself
to wrap that Box Collider.
And you can see on our Box
Collider in our Inspector
it actually has a "Size,"
and that is extremely helpful
because now we
no longer need to guess
what the halfway point is
of our Background.
So, now in our
RepeatBackground Script,
we're going to use another variable,
and this one'll be private since we know
since we know exactly what
we need now, and it'll be a float
since you saw the size
had some decimals in there,
and we're just going to call
it the "repeatWidth".
And so this'll be the width
that we actually repeat at
when we want to reset
our position.
In our Start() method,
we're actually going
to set our repeatWidth
so we'll use repeatWidth,
and we're going to set this to the size
of our Box Collider.
Now, because our Box Collider
is a Component,
we're actually going to need
that "GetComponent<>()" method again.
So we're going to GetComponent<>(),
and now we need
that left and right carat
so that we can get the type
of Component we're looking for.
So in this case, we're
looking for a BoxCollider,
and then we're going
to use our parenthesis
since this is a method.
So now we're getting
the Box Collider on our Object,
and what we want to do
is we can actually get the size
property of that Component.
So if we type in ".size,"
and then we get the actual X size
so then we can get the total width
of our Background,
and we're just looking
for that exact halfway point.
So we'll divide using one
right forward slash
by 2,
and that'll give us half the size,
half the width of our Background.
And then last but not least,
the only thing we need to do
is get rid of this hard-coded
number right here,
and this'll be our repeatWidth.
So now when we save,
now that we're back in Unity,
you can watch
as our happy little Player
runs through the scene,
and it looks like
even though you can see
the scene moving back and forth,
in order to make it look
like it's repeating,
in the Players View,
it looks exactly perfect.
So, now it's your turn.
So what your going to do,
is you're going to apply
a Box Collider on your Background,
and then in our
RepeatBackground Script,
you're going to create
another variable,
a private float called repeatWidth.
You're going to Get your Component
of your BoxCollider
in the Start() method,
and you're going to get
its specific size,
and only on the X-Axis,
and then you're going to divide by 2
so that what you can get
the exact halfway point
of our Background,
and then you're going to change
your hard coded number
to be repeatWidth.
Now it's your turn.
[music]